allstartfitness.com 2017-02-09

# All Start Fitness

## allstartfitness.com Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy describes how we treat user information we collect both online through our allstartfitness.com (the “Site”) and offline, such as through phone or email interactions you have with us. The Site is brought to you by allstartfitness.com (referred to in this Policy as “allstartfitness.com,” “we,” “us,” and “our”).

### Your agreement to this Policy

Your use of the Site signifies that you have read, understand, and agree with all of the terms of this Policy. If you do not agree to all of the terms of this Policy, do not use the Site. You agree that this Policy is supported by reasonable and valuable consideration (including your use of the Site), the receipt and sufficiency of which you acknowledge. 

### Information we collect

a. Personally-Identifying Information. When you use the Site, we collect personally-identifying information (hereafter, “Personal Information”) that you actively enter into the Site. We may also collect Personal Information from you through offline contacts, such as email or phone call. Personal Information may include your name, title, gender, address, phone number, email address, and whatever other personally-identifying information you actively enter into or upload onto the Site.

b. Automatically-Collected Information. As you navigate, browse, and engage in activities on the Site, we automatically collect and store information about your visit to and use of the Site, such as: The date and time of your visit, the duration of your visit, the type of browser and browser language you use, your Internet Protocol (“IP”) or MAC address, your mobile device ID, the type of computer or other operating device used, the actions you take on the Site (such as pages viewed and links clicked), the websites from which you linked to the Site, and the websites you visit after visiting the Site. We use this information in the aggregate to inform us regarding what services and Site features users purchase and look at most frequently. We also use this information as described elsewhere in this Policy. All information discussed in this Section 2(b) is referred to in this Policy as “Automatically-Collected Information.” Unless otherwise stated in this Policy or prohibited by law, Automatically-Collected Information may be combined with your Personal Information.

### We collect information in different ways

You do not have to provide us with your Personal Information to browse the Site, and we only collect Personal Information when you voluntarily provide it. When you do provide us your Personal Information, you are authorizing us to use that information in accordance with this Policy.

We gather Automatically-Collected Information from you passively. We use commonly-used information-gathering tools, such as cookies and web beacons, to collect Automatically-Collected Information as you navigate the Site. 

(i) Cookies. The Site uses a feature of your Internet browser called “cookies” to make your interactions with the Site easy and meaningful. When you visit the Site, our servers send a cookie to your computer or other operating device. The cookie is placed on your hard drive or other operating device, and it assigns your computer or operating device a unique, random number that acts as a sort of anonymous ID. Standing alone, cookies do not personally identify you; rather, a cookie identifies the computer or operating device used to access the Site. A cookie cannot read data off of your hard drive. Unless you choose to identify yourself to us, such as by filling out a web form, you remain anonymous to us when browsing the Site; in other words, the cookie alone will not allow us to identify you personally.

There are two types of cookies: Session-based and persistent-based. Session cookies exist only during one session. They disappear from your computer or operating device when you close your browser software or otherwise end your session. Persistent cookies remain on your computer or operating device after you close your browser or otherwise end your session. We use session cookies to provide us information about Site features used and activities conducted while using the Site. We also use persistent cookies so we can recognize your computer or other operating device when you return to the Site. We also use third-party persistent cookies to help us deliver advertising based on your online activity.

Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can disable the acceptance of cookies at any time by changing the preferences in your browser. Most browsers also allow you to change the settings to require that the browser notify you when you receive a new cookie. Please refer to your browser for information on how to disable and control cookies. If you disable your web browser’s ability to accept cookies, you may not be able to successfully use certain features of the Site. Further, note that in order to stop receiving our advertisements based on your online activity, you will need to opt-out of this online tracking, as described immediately below.

(ii) Third-party cookies and Site analytics; our targeted advertising practices. We use third-party services, including Google Analytics provided by Google, Inc., to track and analyze your Site activity, as well as to track websites you visit after using the Site.. In order to use these third-party services, we use a Google Analytics’ cookie on the Site. The information generated by the Google Analytics’ cookie about your use of the Site (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the Site, compiling reports on Site activity for us, and providing other services relating to Site activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf.

We may also use other third-party services, such as Google AdWords and Google Display Network, to serve online advertisements to you on other websites after you’ve visited the Site. This practice is known as remarketing, and you will see our advertisements across the Internet unless you opt-out, as discussed below. We, along with third-party vendors, Google and DoubleClick, use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics’ cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and deliver advertisements based on your online activity, including your past visits to the Site. If you would like to opt-out of receiving targeted advertising like this from Google, you can manage these settings by visiting the Google Ads settings page. Also, Google recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Ad-on. Alternatively, you can opt-out by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page. Note that even if you opt-out, you may still see our advertisements, but they will not be delivered based on your online activity. 

(iii) Web beacons. We use web beacons alone or in conjunction with cookies to compile Automatically-Collected Information about your use of the Site, as well as your interaction with emails from us. Web beacons are clear electronic images embedded in a web page, website feature, or email, which can recognize certain types of information on your computer or other operating device, such as cookies, when you viewed a particular website tied to the web beacon, and a description of a website tied to the web beacon. For example, we may place web beacons in marketing emails that notify us when you click on a link in the email that directs you to the Site. We use web beacons to operate and improve the Site and email communications and to statistically monitor how many people are using the Site and opening our emails and for what purposes. We do not collect Personal Information with web beacons. 

(iv) IP addresses and mobile device IDs. When you visit the Site, we collect your IP address and mobile device ID to track and aggregate Automatically-Collected Information.

### We use your information as described here

a. We use your Personal Information to respond to your requests or questions, and to otherwise perform the services you request. We may also use your Personal Information to send you transactional communications.

b. We use your Personal Information for marketing purposes.

c. We use Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to improve our Site and services; to help diagnose problems with the Site; and to analyze statistical use patterns and demographic data. We might use Automatically-Collected Information to track what Site users look at most frequently so we can recognize and deliver more of the desired content. We may combine Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information we get from you with information about you that we get from third parties.

d. We use Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information as otherwise described in this Policy and as otherwise permitted by law.

### We may share your information with third parties, as described here.

a. Third-party service providers. We may share your Personal Information with our third-party service providers so that they can contact you on our behalf to perform certain services for us, perform certain marketing on our behalf, and/or perform Site analytics services, as described above, or other services relating to the operation of the Site (such as hosting, data storage, and security). We may also share Personal Information of our users with our service providers to ensure the quality of information provided. These third-party service providers are not authorized to use your information in any way other than as described in this Policy and are required to keep the information confidential. 

b. Merger, acquisition, or sale. We may share or transfer Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to a third-party successor to all or any part of our business. In this event, we will, if allowed, use reasonable efforts to notify you when your information is shared with or transferred to any third party by posting such notice on the Site and/or by contacting you via the Personal Information you have provided us, if any.

c. Required by law. We reserve the right to disclose your Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information if we reasonably believe we are required to do so by law, rule, regulation, judicial proceeding, court order, subpoena, or similar legal process; if we reasonably believe disclosure is necessary to protect, establish, or exercise our rights or property, or to defend against legal claims; or if we reasonably believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our other Site users or our employees, property, or business, or to take action regarding illegal activities or suspected fraud.

d. De-identified information. We may share de-identified, aggregated Automatically-Collected Information without restriction.

e. Public areas of the site. The Site contains areas where users can post content that will be viewed by other users. You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose Personal Information on these areas for public viewing, the information may be collected, stored, used, and disclosed by other users. Such activities are beyond our control, and we shall have no responsibility for or liability regarding the protection or security of such information. Do not post Personal Information that you want to keep private on these areas of the Site.

### Your choices; opt-out rights; correcting and updating your information

You can control your browser’s acceptance of cookies, and you can opt out of receiving targeted online advertising,.

### Retention

We may retain all Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information in our databases for as long as is necessary or relevant for our business, unless applicable laws require otherwise. This includes as long as we need it to complete a transaction or to do the things described in this Policy. You can contact us via the contact information below and ask us to remove your information from our databases. Note that even after you ask us to remove your information from our databases, it may be impossible to remove some information, such as information tracked in our web server log files and information that may reside in backup files. This residual information is retained to preserve the integrity of our files. We may also retain Automatically-Collected Information even after you request that we remove your information from our databases, for use in the aggregate and to analyze and improve the Site. Further, even after you request that we remove your information from our databases, we may retain Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information to comply with any applicable law, rule, regulation, or guideline; to prevent fraudulent activity; to protect ourselves against liability; and to allow us to enforce our contractual or other rights and to pursue available remedies and limit any damages we may sustain.

### Security; Disclaimer

We use standard security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, and alteration of Personal Information and Automatically-Collected Information that is under our control. The standard security measures we take will depend on the type of information collected.

We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. Please do not send us sensitive information via email as this is not secure. Please notify us if you become aware that your Personal Information is lost, stolen, or used without permission.

Unfortunately, no data storage system or system of transmitting data over the Internet or wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure, and no security system can prevent all security breaches. As a result, we do not and cannot guarantee the security of our servers or any Personal Information or Automatically-Collected Information provided to us. Any transmission of your information to us is at your own risk.

### Linked Websites 

We highly recommend that you review the privacy policies of the third-party sites you might link to from our before providing any Personal Information through these third-party sites or otherwise continuing to use these third-party sites. We do not control these websites. We are not responsible for these websites or their owners’ and operators’ practices and use of your information collected as you use the websites.

### What we will do if there is an update to this Policy 

From time to time, we may change our privacy practices and this Policy. We will post any new or revised Policy here, and you can determine if this Policy has been revised since your last visit to the Site by referring to the last updated date at the top of this Policy. Please check the Site regularly for updates. We will also notify you of any material change to this Policy if required by law. Your use of the Site following changes to this Policy constitutes your acceptance of and agreement to the terms of the Policy, as updated by us, and the revisions apply to all information collected on and after the date on which we post the updated Policy. 

### Enforceability

If any part of this Policy is determined to be invalid or unenforceable pursuant to applicable law, then the invalid or unenforceable provision will be deemed superseded by a valid, enforceable provision that most closely matches the intent of the original provision and the remainder of the Policy shall continue in full force and effect.
